In this section we are going to look at AWS Agiantic AI capabilities.
So, one of the core services from AWS on Agiantic AI is Amazon Bedrock agents.
Now, before we deep dive into what are Amazon Bedrock agents,
let's take a look at a formal definition on Bedrock agents.
So, AWS says Amazon Bedrock agents is a fully managed service.
So, what that means is AWS will take care of hosting monitoring, scaling, patching,
and all the other tasks related to agents.
So, Amazon Bedrock agents enables generative AI applications to automate multi-step tasks
by seamlessly connecting with company systems, APIs and data sources.
And, if you look at what we had discussed in the previous section, we had talked about how agents
can autonomously execute multi-step tasks by connecting with external data sources,
internal data sources, through the tools.
So, that's what AWS is highlighting on what Amazon Bedrock agents can do.
Now, let's go and take a look at the core components of Amazon Bedrock agents.
So, we have the agent, and then let's start with the most important planning and reasoning
ability of the agents.
So, Amazon Bedrock agent supports by default reasoning and action style of planning along
with chain of thought reasoning.
So, in the previous section, we had already discussed about chain of thought reasoning
and reason and actual style of planning.
So, if you're not gone through that lecture, please go through that lecture for basics in
the previous section.
Now, let me go ahead and deep dive a little more into how Amazon Bedrock agents actually
implements reasoning and action style of planning.
So, in one of the previous sections, we had looked at this use case when we were doing
the AI agent planning demo.
So, we said the user is going on a 5-day vacation and he sent this request to the microcool
AI agent and then this microcool agent has two capabilities to check the leave balance of
the employee and then book a hotel.
And then we had posed this question where we said, okay, book a hotel room for me with
employee ID this and if the leave balance is more than three days, then book a hotel.
Now, if you remember, there were three key actions that the AI agent had to take.
So, check my leave balance from my HR system table, then make a determination if the
leave balance is less or more than three days and then third, if the leave balance is
less than three days, then tell me that the hotel room cannot be booked and it's more
than three days, then book the hotel room.
Okay, with this example, now let's see, how this will be implemented in Amazon bedrock agents.
So, here we are looking at the react orchestration style.
So, sometimes it's called as react orchestration style or it can also be called as react
prompting style.
So, those are some of the keywords that we will often hear.
Now we are the Amazon bedrock agents, so we have something known as orchestrator.
So, you can think of orchestrator as some internal code that AWS has written for the purpose
of orchestration.
So, either you can use the default orchestrator that AWS has, but it also allows you to
write the custom orchestrator in AWS Lambda function if required.
Now, let's see what this orchestrator does and how does it interact with the large language
model which is driving the agent.
Okay, so the first thing this orchestrator will do is it will send the user request.
So, as we saw in the previous example, the user wanted to book a hotel room based on the
number of leaves.
So, what this orchestrator will do is it will send the user request and all the tools
it has.
So, maybe it has a tool to check the leave balance from HR system, maybe it has a tool
to check, whether maybe it has a tool which makes a booking reservation in a hotel.
So, it will send the user request plus tools to this LLM that is driving the agent and
then the LLM is going to analyze and then LLM is going to respond with what is the action
that needs to be taken next.
So, what will happen is like in our case, the first thing it's going to do is it's going
to make a call to the HR backend system for leave balance.
Now, let's say it has got the leave balance which says the your leave balance is 10 days.
Next, this orchestrator is going to send the user request, the tools and the observation
that it got from this step which is what is my leave balance.
So, then it's going to say okay the leave balance of the employees is 10 days and then
the LLM is going to provide it what is the next action it needs to take.
And in this case, since the leave balance is more than 3 days, so it's going to tell it
go ahead and make a call to the hotel booking API and book the hotel.
And then the orchestrator does that and once it gets the observation from the hotel booking
API, it's going to send this request, the tools it has and the previous and the new observation
to the agent and then agent is going to come back with its recommendation.
And in this case, it's going to be the final result.
And as we had seen in the demo in the previous section that it will come back with the booking
ID.
So that is how the reasoning and action orchestration style works in Amazon bedrock agents.
Now if you see the react, so it's sometimes called as orchestrator style or prompting style,
it defines the plan and then modifies as we go but it is sequential in nature.
So now hopefully you understood that though it is dynamic, so let's say in this section
it had said leave days is only two, so it would have taken a different action.
But if the leave number of leave days is more than three, then it will take a different
action.
So though it is dynamic in nature, but it is still sequential, okay.
The second planning style that Amazon bedrock agent supports is custom.
So what custom means is that you can write your own orchestration or prompting style.
And one of the common ones is reasoning without observation or sometimes called as re-woo.
And why would you want to use a different style of orchestration?
And the reason is if you see the scenario that we had discussed previously, it was sequential
in nature.
So first the orchestrator send the request to the LLM agent, maybe if you are using something
like cloud or a large language model, it will take three seconds maybe at least to do
the processing then in the next step, it will again send this and there will be more processing
and then again it is going to send.
So it might be five to ten seconds before the user actually gets a response in complex processing
scenarios.
And if it is a chatbot, then the customer might not have a great user experience.
So in some scenarios, you might just need to send the request once to the large language
model and then it tells you steps and then you just go ahead and feedback that response
to the end user.
You don't need to do back and forth with the LLM.
So one common example that it always provides for reasoning without observation is let's
say you want to book dinner reservation.
So the only two things you have to do is let's say you want to get a menu and you want
to book a table for a particular date.
So once you send the request to the agent, it's going to call the restaurant reservation,
book the table for you and then send you the menu.
So maybe it needs to send that request only once to the large language model to save on
the response time.
Okay.
Now the second one is memory.
So the bedrock agents are enabled with both long term memory and shorter memory and long
term memory can be used to store the user conversation up to 365 days.
So long term memory is managed by AWS and all you need to do is define whether it's true
or false and it will store the long term conversation between the user and the agent.
Next is the shorter memory again this is enabled by AWS by default all the interaction
between the end user and the agent within that particular session are going to be stored
and those user inputs are also going to be passed on to the tools that you might be using
and are integrated with the agent.
Okay.
Next is the tools and action AWS provide three kind of tools.
So the first one is the action group and this is critical.
So here you can use a combination of AWS Lambda and open API schema.
So once we build the use cases in the next few sections then you are going to be able
to visualize how we can use these action groups to connect to external and internal data
sources.
And then you have the bedrock knowledge basis and we've already discussed the managed
rag based solution from AWS and knowledge basis can be integrated with agents which allow
the end user to access unstructured data in form of PDFs and so on.
Then finally you have the code interpreter.
So a common scenario would be, so let's say you have a docs agent and it's monitoring
few applications within your environment.
So now let's say there is an incident.
So what this dev app agent can do is it can analyze what's the root cause of the agent
using the LLM then generate the code and then it can test out that code in the code
interpreter which is a local sandbox environment.
And if it works there then it can implement that patch.
So that is what code interpreter can be used for.
So then you have the communication.
So we have the single agent and it also supports multi agent orchestration.
So sometimes the application that you might be building with agents might be really complicated
and the agent could have large number of tools maybe tens and hundreds of tools.
Then it might be difficult for a single agent to route the user request accurately.
And in that scenario we can use multiple agents and then AWS provides you with a multi
agent orchestration framework which helps you in routing to these multiple agents and
also helping with the coordination and collaboration between these different agents.
And then finally with the agent guardrails.
So Amazon bedrock service already has a capability where you can build customized guardrails
for hallucination detection or toxicity detection and control.
So you can build the guardrails from the bedrock service and then integrated with the
Amazon bedrock agents.
Okay that's pretty much it from what are the core components of Amazon bedrock agents.
I'll see you in the next lecture, thank you.